[Music]
We're fourth-generation farmers
from Mildura.
My grandfather and great-grandfather,
and dad, have all been involved
in farming this way.
Dad bought these farms in this region
back in 1969 and started his own business
from there.
Around the late '80s, he was having
some problems with soil compaction,
and just a decline in the trees
and so forth.
His sister pointed him
towards biodynamic farming.
The first farm was certified biodynamic
in 1989,
Since then, it's been a lifestyle
and philosophy we've run with.
It's now my brother Rob and myself
who own and run the business.
In 2009, I suppose we were probably
somewhere around 550, 600 acres.
Over the following three years,
we expanded and expanded and expanded,
and we've ended up now with 1,300 acres:
just under 400 acres of citrus,
around 500 acres of almonds,
15 acres of avocados,
and this big beast
of a biodynamic farming operation.
We just want to produce
the best-quality fruit we can,
whether organic, conventional
or biodynamic.
It's all about taste and flavour.
Producing a nice, nutrient-dense fruit
probably relates to eating quality.
The better the fruit tastes,
that's going to bring return customers
and drive profitability in the business.
As the farming industry changes,
people want to know this
paddock-to-plate stuff.
They want to get in touch and in contact
with who it is that's growing their fruit,
what their properties look like,
and be actively involved
or emotionally tied
to the actual farm itself.
Regenerative farming
will matter more,
looking after the soil
and being potentially carbon neutral.
People will drive and push us as farmers
to look after the land a lot better
than what we have.
Climate change is obviously
a massive issue.
Farming is probably one industry
that can fix it straight away,
if we really wanted to,
across the world.
We originally brought them on board
around 2011, I think it was.
The main reason was a change in some
of the composting we were using.
We were putting out straight cow manure,
and quite a lot of it.
We talked to Hybrid Ag
about what they could do for us,
We found a few tweaks
in the compost blend
could significantly reduce the amount
we were putting out.
So we decided to give it a go,
and we did see some great results
straight up.
That relationship's only grown,
especially over the last three
or four years.
Tom and I often sit down in the office
and have a bit of a chinwag about life,
philosophies about farming,
and what we should be doing
to look after the land and the soil,
and leave it better
than we started.
Having that trust with him,
and what he believes,
That gives us the flexibility
to let him take charge of some areas,
and areas we're not happy with.
It's a nice, smooth, easy relationship.
It's happy days from my point of view.
[Music]
Hybrid Ag. Transforming food for health.